EDGAR GONZALEZ

4-74 48th Ave. Apt 17E, Long Island City, NY 11109 | 917-216-1585 edgargonzalez@gmail.com http://gonzalez.io | http://github.com/edgar

SUMMARY

Father, husband, and software engineer with more than 25 years of experience.

I'm building web applications since 1994 for a living and I love it.

Rubyist, Rails developer since 2006, believer of Agile Development and Lean startups, NoSQL enthusiast, iOS developer padawan and Golang developer apprentice

I went through the TechStars NY startup accelerator program with Piictu (Summer 2011).

TOP SKILLS

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, Docker, RESTful APIs design, Architecture design on AWS (SQS, SNS, Kinesis, ...), MySQL, Redis, ElasticSearch, Kibana, Logstash, MongoDB, Varnish, JavaScript, Go, Swift, Obj-C, Java, ...

EXPERIENCE

Apr 2013 - Present Engineering Lead, StreetEasy / Zillow

- · As Engineering Lead, my core responsibilities centered around improving StreetEasy's architecture, leading the transition to a (micro)services-oriented architecture, managing the DevOps team, the Data Integrity team an also the Mobile team, and being in charge of the mobile API.
- · Led the project that reduced StreetEasy's total AWS cost by 48%.

Jul 2013 - Present

Senior Software Engineer (part time), Kaplan Test Prep

 \cdot Part-time - Web / Mobile application consultant.

May 2012 - Present Technical Mentor, Wayra Venezuela

 Wayra is a Telefónica initiative whose main objective is to identify talent in Spain and Latin America in the field of New Technologies of Information and Communication Technologies (TICs) and encourage them in their development through comprehensive support, giving the entrepreneurs the tools, space and funding needed.

Nov 2011-Apr 2013 Co-Founder & CTO, Piictu

- Piictu was a free photo-sharing mobile app. Users were encouraged to capture an image on their phone and share it to a subject-appropriate "stream" (or album). All streams were public, and users were encouraged to reply to a subject with topical pictures creating a photo-conversation.
- Responsible for all aspects of overall technology vision and architecture and backend lead developer: REST API (Ruby on Rails), Heroku, OAuth2, MongoDB, Redis, Amazon S3, Amazon CloudFront, etc.
- Piictu joined Kandu (a Betaworks company): http://techcrunch.com/2013/05/22/photo-app-service-piictu-to-join-betaworks-company-kandu-will-shut-down-on-may-31st/

Feb 2009-Feb 2012 Senior Lecturer, Central University of Venezuela

· Senior Lecturer of Web Application Development at Computer Sciences School, Faculty of Science.

Nov 1996-Jul 2012 Co-Founder & CTO, has_many :developers

 has_many :developers is a workshop specialized in develop Web and Mobile Applications. We are expert Ruby on Rails developers and NOSQL enthusiasts

May 1996-Nov 1996 Technical Consultant – Web Developer, Oracle

 Develop a web application (the first one in the Venezuelan Oil & Gas industry) to analyze the daily production of barrels of liquefied gas, using the Oracle Web Server.

Jun 1995-May 1996 SAP/ABAP Consultant, IMG Consultores

• Report development, data interfaces, analysis and design, and dialog programming in the SAP R/3 environment, including integration between SAP and non-SAP systems.

Oct 1992-Jun 1995 Project Leader, Consein C.A.

• Coordinate and develop the Car Insurance module for Seguros Caracas (Liberty Mutual). Using Oracle CASE and Oracle Development Suite

Feb 1989-Oct 1992 Analyst, Aluen, Uribe & Asoc.

• Developing a PC networking for Banking Industry, thru serial port (Protocols according ISO model, low level signaling handshaking, signal timer, I/O serial registers, Assembler 8080 coding, etc). Interaction against midrange IBM hardware (IBM 9370). Support for Home Banking application.

HONOR & AWARDS

Jan 2015 Hackweek - Best Product Improvement, StreetEasy / Zillow.

· Proof of concept to use ElasticSearch to power listing searches.

Jun 2014 Hackweek - Best Process Improvement/Internal Tool, StreetEasy / Zillow.

 Add line profiler (rblineprof) and webconsole to the StreetEasy web app (for development and staging environments).

Mar 2014 Zuperstar Award Q1/2014, StreetEasy / Zillow.

Jun 1992 Graduated Cum Laude in Computer Science, Central University of Venezuela.

· Ranked first in graduating class.

EDUCATION

1986-1992 Licentiate on Computer Science, Central University of Venezuela.

· A Licentiate's degree comprises four years of study in Computer Science plus one year for the thesis.